Guide to the Ron Padgett Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- February 2009 Acquistion, 1929-2008; (89 boxes)
  - Full Court Press, 1929, 1971-1992
    The Full Court Press archive comprises all extant correspondence, manuscripts, proofs, production materials, promotion files and business records (from incorporation to dissolution) of the Full Court Press.
    - Files A-F, 1929, 1974-1980; 2 (Box 61)
      1929 copy of Philippe Soupault's Last Nights of Paris.
      Miscellaneous papers and letters
    - Files A-F (continued), 1974-1987; 9 (Box 62)
      "A"
      Materials for Ad
      Avenue Reprint
      Books in Print
      Bindery
      "B"
      Book Fair
      Bulk Mail
      Burroughs
      "C"
      Capital City Press
      Catalogues / Flyers
      Blank contracts
      "D"
      Distributors
      "E"
      "F"
      Flyer No. 1, No. 2
    - Files G-Z, 1975-1983; 3 (Box 62)
      Frank O'Hara Award Series / Columbia
      "G"
      John Godfrey
      "H"
      Mildred Hird
      ISBN
      Ivy Hill
      "I"
      "J"
      "K"
      Mike Kasser
      John Koethe
      "L"
      "M"
    - Files G-Z (continued), 1974-1982; 8 (Box 63)
      Mailing lists
      National book awards
      NEA
      NY Book Fair
      NY State Council on the Arts
      NY State Small Press Association
      "N"
      "O"
      Frank O'Hara
      Press Releases
      "Q"
      "R"
      "S"
      Soupault
      "T"
      "U"
      "V"
      "W X Y Z"
      W. M.S./P.S. flyer for MLA
    - Manuscripts A-N, circa 1976-1981; 3 (Box 63)
      Burroughs mansucript
      WSB Xerox
      Cohen manuscript
      Extra Cohen xerox
      Extra Godfrey Dabble
    - Manuscripts A-N (continued), circa 1976-1981; 9 (Box 64)
      Fagin manscript
      F. O'Hara manuscript
      "Dabble"
      Kerouac manuscript
      Joe Leshear manuscript
      "The Fox" by Jack Collins
    - Manuscripts N-Z, circa 1973-1980s; 2 (Box 64)
      Ratcliff mansucript
      Stanton Stories
    - Manuscripts N-Z (continued), circa 1973-1980s; 3 (Box 65)
      Stanton manuscript "Mangled Hands"
      Stanton - Strange Tales
      World Anthology
      Wertheim Typographers Co., Inc.
    - Miscellaneous 1/3, 1975-1986; 6 (Box 65)
      Photos
      Newspapers / Clippings
      Lally article
      Other newspaper articles
      Soupault and Godfrey
      Veitch and Kirkus 8/1/78
      Tom Veitch / Booklist 4/15/79
      WSB Review - A-B 5/24/82
      O'Hara Library Journal
      O'Hara review - SoHo 4/26/79
      O'Hara - Boston Globe
      O'Hara booklist
      Reviews - originals
      Other newspapers
      Reviewers
    - Miscellaneous 1/3 (continued), 1975-1983; 11 (Box 66)
      WSB Review
      Other reviews / clippings
      NEA application materials
      Financial records
      Permissions
      FCP Royalty worksheets
      Cash Flow
      Other
      Debts
      Inventory
      MO Cohen
      Invoices
      Address book
      Subchapters
      FCP investors
      Finacial records
      Newspapers and others
    - Miscellaneous 2/3, 1974-1983; 3 (Box 66)
      Denby / Brandeis Award
      Edwin promo
      Denby
      Joan S.
      1977 Taxes
      1978 Taxes
      S. Vlahakas
      1981-1982 Tax Info (for Vlahakas)
    - Miscellaneous 2/3 (continued), 1971-1992; 7 (Box 67)
      Taxes 1986-1987
      Tax Return 1987
      1985 Taxes
      CT-6-I / Shareholder
      "1979 Taxes (missing) / Vlahakas must have" folder
      1980 Taxes
      1981 Taxes
      1982 Taxes
      1984 Taxes
      1983 Taxes
      FCP ad
      Rebounds / Publishers Weekly 10/23/78
      FCP debt
      FCP correspondence
      Full Court - extra royalty
      Extra royalty statements
      Royalty statements
      Photos and Negatives
      Dissolution Papers
      Archives of FCP
      Royalty Statements
      Royalties
      Clippings
    - Miscellaneous 3/3, 1973-1984; 2 (Box 67)
      "I Remember"
      Full Court Press booklet
    - Miscellaneous 3/3 (continued), 1973-1984; 9 (Box 68)
      Denby manuscript
      Contract
      Full Court Press proof
      Corporate Record Book
      Stock
      Incorporation
      Publisher's Weekly
      Correspondence
      "The Luis Armed Story"
      Guru Blues
      First Blues
      Luis Armed Story
      First Blues cover
      Ron Padgett Letters and others
      Sesheta
      Paperback Talk 9/20/82
      "Sets of early reviews for third series"
  - Teaching Files, 1960s-2000
    - Miscellaneous Teaching, 1970s; 8 (Box 69)
    - Miscellaneous and Articles, 1960s-1970s; 5 (Box 69)
    - Magazines and Anthologies, 1970s; 3 (Box 69)
    - Magazines and Anthologies (continued), 1970s; 4 (Box 70)
    - MUSE Teaching, 1970s; 2 (Box 70)
    - MINN, YMHA, & C. Teaching, 1970s; 6 (Box 70)
    - Delaware Spring 1975; Shue; Ogletown and Gamger. Middle Schools., 3 (Box 70)
    - Delaware Spring 1975; Shue; Ogletown and Gamger. Middle Schools. (continued), 3 (Box 71)
    - Holmdel, NJ; 217 Brooklyn, etc. Teaching., 1974; 5 (Box 71)
    - TAP & WIC, So. Car. Teaching, 1970s; 7 (Box 71)
    - TAP & WIC, So. Car. Teaching, 1976-1977; 7 (Box 72)
    - TAP Journal 1-4 (complete) & TAP & WIC Stuff, 1970s; 6 (Box 72)
    - "Structure & Style II Spring '87", "Central Middle School Spring '75" and Poetry Project, 1975-1987 (Box 72)
    - "Structure & Style II Spring '87", "Central Middle School Spring '75" and Poetry Project (continued), 1975-1987; 7 (Box 73)
    - PS 61 Teaching, 1970s; 7 (Box 73)
    - PS 19 - Atlantic Center for the Arts, 1970s-1990s; 2 (Box 73)
    - PS 19 - Atlantic Center for the Arts (continued), 1970s-1990s; 15 (Box 74)
    - PS 19 - Atlantic Center for the Arts, 1970s-1990s (Box 75)
    - Columbia Teaching, 1995; 6 (Box 75)
    - Columbia Teaching, 1996; 6 (Box 75)
    - Columbia Teaching, 1997; 5 (Box 75)
    - Brooklyn College - Spring, 1999-2000; 4 (Box 76)
  - Personal and Professional Papers, 1947-2008
    - Grade School Papers and Report Cards, 1947-1960; 4 (Box 77)
    - College Papers and Notebooks, 1961-1976; 6 (Box 77)
    - Post College manuscripts, 1965-1966; 2 (Box 77)
    - Saginaw, MI Residency, 1983-1997 (Box 77)
    - Saginaw, MI Residency (continued), 1983-1997; 2 (Box 78)
      Also includes correspondence, lecture notes and annoucements regarding the Unversity of California, circa 1985, the US-China Arts Exchange program, the St. Marks Translation workshop (circa 1983) and the Guggenheim (circa 1985).
    - Ron's T&W work Calendars, 1983-2000; 6 (Box 78)
    - Appointment books, 1971-1976; 3 (Box 78)
    - Appointment books, 1972-1977; 4 (Box 78)
    - Appointment books, 1978-1991; 14 (Box 79)
    - Appointment books, 1992-2002; 11 (Box 80)
    - Students on Tulsa Kid, 1995 (Box 80)
    - Living Room File Cabinet, 1962-2008; 12 (Box 81)
      Reverdy Prose Poems
      Reverdy handwritten revisions
      Serge manuscript and correspondence
      Engelope - Allentown Community Center Project
      [Paul Morand], translation
      OO LA LA - project with Jim Dine
      Ron's Full Court (personal) letters
      Manuscript for Mark Polizzotti
      Dada in Paris
      Poems - Putney 3/72
      Celery Stalks at Midnight, correspondence with Ed Sanders
      No Title, manuscript, 1971-1972
      Star Gut (brown binder)
      The Care and Feeding of a Child's Imagination
      Envelope - Interview, biblio, statement
      FCP - Warrant, business
      Elmslie work for Ron Padgett's birthday
      Envelope, Ed Foster INterview
      OO LA LA (business only)
      Ron Padgett interviews
      "Poems I Guess I Wrote"
      NYC Ballet 2/98
      "Wishes" Preface
      "Song in G" with Dorny
      Dorney's "Synesthesia"
      NY Times Piece
      Manuscript sent to Charlottesville, Oct 20, 1972
      Misc - Others + List '69 AIS Poets
      Story in Black and WHite
      Living Room file Cab drawers 2005
      Young Pieces
      10 Typed poems, interview with Bruce Weber
      W.S.B. Roosevelt, "Roots" by Berkson
      "Royal Blue For The Boys"
      Poems by George Schneeman
      Zohra Saed manuscript
      Mr. Flint - abandoned collaboration with Tom Veitch
      Blue "Tulsa Kid" Folder
      World of Leon cover
      Material for Joe B. "Selected Writings" cover
      "How to Be Perfect" proofs
      "If I Were You" proofs
      "Dream Journal" (1962)
      "Robert Creeley Journal"
      Spoof with RP, JB, KE, Pat Padgett (1960s?)
      Miscellaneous unsorted
      Paris 1966
      "Gray Sky"
      "Readings outside of NYC mostly"
      Toujours L'Amour
    - Living Room File Cabinet (continued), 1962-2008; 10 (Box 82)
    - Living Room File Cabinet (continued), 1962-2008 (Box 83)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, 1973-1992; 4 (Box 84)
      Poetry Project 1978-80
      Miscellaneous business correspondence and grant applications
      Manuscript for Selected Poems
      Application for a Witter Bynner grant for Cendrars translation
      Literary business correspondence, in and out
      Article for Collier's Encyclopedia on Kenneth Koch: manuscripts, notes, correspondence
      Manuscripts and notes for residency at 80 Langdon Street, San Francisco, 1980
      Letters and notes for southern California reading tourn, Nov. 1980
      Notes and correspondence towards a Ron Padgett Reader for Paragon House
      Notes and papers re: Conference in Paris, 1981
    - Fairfield Porter Letters, photocopies, 11 (Box 85)
    - J. Schuyler Diary, photocopies, circa 1996 (Box 85)
    - Manuscript material removed from books, 1966-2005; 75 (Box 86)
      Armantrout, Rae. ALS to Padgett, (no date)
      Barnes, R.G. ALS to Padgett (1996)
      Barnes, R.G. TLS to Padgett (1994)
      Barwin, Gary. ALS to Padgett (no date)
      Brownstein, Michael. APC tp Padgett (1978)
      Chapman, Lee. ANS to Padgett (1994)
      Page torn out of an undated work (no date)
      Colby, Todd. ALS to Padgett (1992)
      Carey, Steve. APcS to Padgett (no date)
      Coolidge, Clark. ALS to Ron and Patty Padgett (2001)
      Cooper, Dennis. TLS to Padgett (no date)
      Envelope with address of Dennis Cooper and Ron Padgett (no date)
      Phillips, John. APcS to Padgett (2000)
      Arte Publico Press Invoice to Padgett (1988)
      Bamberger, Bill. APcS to Padgett (no date)
      DeSilver, Albert. TLS to Padgett (no date)
      Ardinger, Richard to Padgett (2001)
      Portion of Envelope with Rackstraw Downes' address (no date)
      Edelstein, Leo. ALS to Padgett (1966)
      Portion of Envelope with Andrew Epstein's address (no date)
      Equi, Elaine. APcS to Padgett (1998)
      Friedman, Michael. ALS to Padgett (2004)
      Friedman, Michael. ALS to Padgett (1992)
      Pearlstein, Darlene. APcS to Padgett (1975)
      Portion of Envelope with Gloria Frym's address (no date)
      Portion of Envelope with Michael Gizzi's address (no date)
      Harding, Gunnar. ALS to Padgett (1995)
      Hill, Owen. ALS to Padgett (1996)
      Portion of Envelope with Anselem Hollo's address (no date)
      Envelope addressed to Padgett from Ray Johnson (no date)
      Review slip signed by Aaron Kiely (no date)
      Envelope addressed to Padgett from publishers (1966)
      Kowit, Steve. ALS to Padgett (1985)
      Kowit, Steve. ALS to Padgett (no date)
      Leites, Edmund. APcS to Padgett (1986)
      Portion of Envelope with Steve Luttrel's address (no date)
      Ratcliffe, Stephen. ALS to Padgett (1995)
      Timken, Jane. ACS to Padgett (no date)
      Corbet, Bill. ALS to Padgett (2001)
      Portion of Envelope with Gillian McCain's address (no date)
      Envelope addressed to Padgett from Dave Morice (no date)
      Kulchur Foundation publisher's card
      Author's Complement card - Penniless Politics
      Olson, John. TLS to Padgett (no date)
      Packer, Eve. TLS to Padgett (1995)
      Pettet. Simon. ALS to Padgett (1995)
      Polizzotti, Mark. ALS to Ron Padgett (1996)
      Portion of Envelope with Stephen Ratcliffe's address
      Raworth, Tom. ACS to Padgett (no date)
      Portion of Envelope with Kit Robinson's Address
      Ross, Stuart. TLS to Padgett (1996)
      Citadel Press publisher's card (1968)
      Newspaper clipping - including The Musical School (1968)
      Schlessinger, John. ALS to Padgett (1996)
      Gibbs Smith Publisher. TLS (Monica Milward) to Padgett (2000)
      Smith, Fred. TLS to Padgett (2004)
      Topp, Mike. ALS to Ron Padgett (no date)
      Topp, Mike. ANS to Padgett (1991)
      Trinidad, David. TLA to Padgett (2000)
      Waldman, Anne. ALS to Padgett (1995)
      Portion of Envelope with Burning Deck's address
      Compliments of Lewis Warsh and Ferry Press publishers (1971)
      Wasserman, Jo-Ann. ACS to Padett with typed poems (1999)
      Williams, Jonathan. TLS to Padgett (1997)
      Portion of Envelope with Arshile's address
      Envelope inscribed with "Ron and Patty Padgett"
      Lautterbach, Anne. ACL to Padgett (1991)
      Newspaper clipping (1975)
      Friedman, Ed. APcS to Padgett (1995)
      Portion of Envelope with Michael Gizzi address
      Corbett, William. ACS to Padgett (1993)
      Invitation to a reading of Godlike, by Richard Hell (2005)
      Yau, John. TLS to Padgett (1993)
      Waldman, Anne. APcS to Padgett (1995)
      Sanders, Ed. ALS to Padgett (no date)
  - Oversize, 1980s
    - Full Court Press - Granary Books - 1PC, 1980s (Box 87)
    - Full Court Press - Granary Books - 1PC, 1980s (Box 88)
  - Restricted Fragile Material
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Computer disks, 3 (Box 89)